<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Goal Recognition | Prof. Sebastian Sardina</title>
    <link>https://ssardina.github.io/tag/goal-recognition/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://ssardina.github.io/tag/goal-recognition/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Goal Recognition</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>2022</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://ssardina.github.io/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Goal Recognition</title>
      <link>https://ssardina.github.io/tag/goal-recognition/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Business Processes &amp; AI</title>
      <link>https://ssardina.github.io/project/bpm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ssardina.github.io/project/bpm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this area we combine AI and Business Processes processes together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One line of work involves using AI planning and agent-oriented systems to obtain more powerful BPM frameworks, for example, by enhancing dynamic adaptation or performing conformance checking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another line of work involves using BPM models and techniques for cost-based goal recognition, which allows us to perform intention recognition without a plan library or PDDL models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some representative papers are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Artem Polyvyanyy, Zihang Su, Nir Lipovetzky, Sebastian Sardiña:
Goal Recognition Using Off-The-Shelf Process Mining Techniques. AAMAS 2020: 1072-1080&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Andrea Marella, Massimo Mecella, and Sebastian Sardina. Intelligent process adaptation in the SmartPM system. ACM Transactions on Intelligent Systems and Technology (ACM TIST) 8(2): 25:1-25:43 (2017).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Giuseppe De Giacomo, Fabrizio Maria Maggi, Andrea Marrella, Sebastian Sardiña: Computing Trace Alignment against Declarative Process Models through Planning. ICAPS 2016: 367-375.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Andrea Marrella, Massimo Mecella, and Sebastian Sardina. SmartPM: An adaptive process management system through situation calculus, indigolog, and classical planning. In Chitta Baral and Giuseppe De Giacomo, editors, Proceedings of Principles of Knowledge Representation and Reasoning (KR), pages 518-527, Vienna, Austria, 2014.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Giuseppe De Giacomo, Fabrizio Maria Maggi, Andrea Marrella, and Sebastian Sardina. Computing trace alignment against declarative process models through planning. In Proceedings of the International Conference on Automated Planning and Scheduling (ICAPS), pages 367&amp;ndash;375, 2016.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goal-Intention Recognition</title>
      <link>https://ssardina.github.io/project/gr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ssardina.github.io/project/gr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The goal/intention recognition problem is the task of identifying an agent’s intent by observing its behaviour. Traditionally, the problem has involved matching a sequence of observations to a plan in a pre-defined plan library; the winning plan being the one that &amp;ldquo;best&amp;rdquo; matches the observations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent developments dispense with the overhead of a plan library and instead&amp;mdash;based on the assumption that the observed agent is behaving rationally&amp;mdash;take a cost-based approach and uses classical planning technology to generate candidate plans as needed over a domain model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a series of work, we have extended and improved the cost-based approach to goal recognition, both for general task planning and path planning. We have worked on how to make recognition faster and more robust to irrational/erratic observed behavior. We have also looked at its&#39; dual problem: &lt;em&gt;deceptive behavior&lt;/em&gt;, the problem of generating behavior that is as deceptive as possible, while still achieving the intended objective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some representative papers are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Peta Masters, Sebastian Sardiña: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0004370221000412?via%3Dihub&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Expecting the unexpected: Goal recognition for rational and irrational agents&lt;/a&gt;. Artificial Intelligence. 297: 103490 (2021)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Artem Polyvyanyy, Zihang Su, Nir Lipovetzky, Sebastian Sardiña: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dl.acm.org/doi/abs/10.5555/3398761.3398886&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Goal Recognition Using Off-The-Shelf Process Mining Techniques&lt;/a&gt;. AAMAS 2020: 1072-1080&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Peta Masters, Sebastian Sardiña: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://jair.org/index.php/jair/article/view/11343&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Cost-Based Goal Recognition in Navigational Domains&lt;/a&gt;. Journal Artificial Intelligence Research 64: 197-242 (2019)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Peta Masters, Sebastian Sardiña: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ijcai.org/proceedings/2017/610&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Deceptive Path-Planning&lt;/a&gt;. IJCAI 2017: 4368-4375.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
