<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Prof. Sebastian Sardina</title>
    <link>https://ssardina.github.io/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://ssardina.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>2022</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://ssardina.github.io/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://ssardina.github.io/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI 4 Education</title>
      <link>https://ssardina.github.io/project/ai4edu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ssardina.github.io/project/ai4edu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We developed a set of 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/AI4EDUC/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;tools&lt;/a&gt; to run daily competitions in our AI courses. Students rely on an improved version of that from 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://ai.berkeley.edu/project_overview.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Berkley AI Pacman framework&lt;/a&gt;. They use search algorithms, Planning Domain Description Language (PDDL), classical replanning, minimax, reinforcement learning, and other approaches for their autonomous Pacman agents. In the course 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://ai.berkeley.edu/contest.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Capture the Flag project&lt;/a&gt;, the objective is to get home as much food as possible and prevent the other team to do so!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The code to run the competitions have been adapted over different games. This project has been developed over the years in collaboration with 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://nirlipo.github.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Dr. Nir Lipovetzky&lt;/a&gt; (Melbourne University).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every year, the top performers from both uni make it to the Hall of Fame and compete for the glory!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Behavior Composition</title>
      <link>https://ssardina.github.io/project/behcomp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ssardina.github.io/project/behcomp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With computers now present in everyday devices like mobile phones, credit cards, cars and planes or places like homes, offices and factories, the trend is to build embedded complex systems from a collection of simple components. A complex surveillance system for a smart house can be then “realised” (i.e., implemented) by suitably coordinating the behaviours (i.e., the operational logic) of hundreds (or thousands) of simple devices and artifacts (e.g., lights, blinds, a microwave, a vacuum cleaner, video cameras, a floor cleaning robot, etc.) installed in the house.  The problem then is how to automatically build an embedded controller-coordinator to bring about a desired target complex system by suitably coordinating the available components.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Behavior composition is not restricted to smart environments and can also be applied to build complex systems in advanced manufacturing systems, web-services, or even in video games, for story generation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A short (fairly easy to read) &lt;strong&gt;overview paper&lt;/strong&gt; on the topic and a more &lt;strong&gt;in-depth journal article&lt;/strong&gt; on the topic are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Giuseppe De Giacomo, Fabio Patrizi, and Sebastian Sardina. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aaai.org/ocs/index.php/ICAPS/ICAPS14/paper/view/8665&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Building virtual behaviors from partially controllable available behaviors in nondeterministic environments&lt;/a&gt;. In Proceedings of the International Conference on Automated Planning and Scheduling (ICAPS), pages 523-526, Portsmouth, NH, USA, 2014. AAAI Press.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Giuseppe De Giacomo, Fabio Patrizi, and Sebastian Sardina. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0004370212001658?via%3Dihub&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Automatic behavior composition synthesis&lt;/a&gt;. Artificial Intelligence Journal, 196:106-142, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A tutorial on the topic delivered at IJCAI&#39;15 can be found 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sites.google.com/site/behaviorcomposition&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
