<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Prof. Sebastian Sardina</title>
    <link>https://ssardina.github.io/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://ssardina.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>2022</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://ssardina.github.io/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://ssardina.github.io/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced forms of AI Planning</title>
      <link>https://ssardina.github.io/project/aiplanning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ssardina.github.io/project/aiplanning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Automated_planning_and_scheduling&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Automated planning&lt;/a&gt; is the problem of automatically producing a plan (i.e., a course of actions) in order to achieve a certain goal (e.g., have all the packages delivered in a logistic domain). Those plans are generally meant to be executed by intelligent agents, autonomous robots, unmanned vehicles, or complex embedded systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am particularly interested in &lt;strong&gt;advanced forms of planning&lt;/strong&gt; (e.g., such as planning under non-determinism or adaptive planning), the &lt;strong&gt;link with controller synthesis&lt;/strong&gt; for adversarial planning, and &lt;strong&gt;path-planning&lt;/strong&gt; (or pathfinding) in an AI context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together with students, and sometimes as part of the &lt;em&gt;COSC1024/2048 Agent-Oriented Programming&lt;/em&gt; course, we developed path-planning libraries and simulation-visualisation toolkit (that are compatible with 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://movingai.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Moving-AI&lt;/a&gt; benchmark framework).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some representative papers in the area are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ivan D. Rodriguez, Blai Bonet, Sebastian Sardiña, Hector Geffner: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ojs.aaai.org/index.php/ICAPS/article/view/15973&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Flexible FOND Planning with Explicit Fairness Assumptions&lt;/a&gt;. ICAPS 2021: 290-29. Best Paper Award.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Daniel Alfredo Ciolek, Nicolás D&amp;rsquo;Ippolito, Alberto Pozanco, Sebastian Sardiña:
[
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ojs.aaai.org//index.php/ICAPS/article/view/6646&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Multi-Tier Automated Planning for Adaptive Behavior&lt;/a&gt;]. ICAPS 2020: 66-74&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nicolás D&amp;rsquo;Ippolito, Natalia Rodríguez, Sebastian Sardiña:

&lt;a href=&#34;https://jair.org/index.php/jair/article/view/11183&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Fully Observable Non-deterministic Planning as Assumption-Based Reactive Synthesis&lt;/a&gt;. Journal of Artificial Intelligence Research, 61: 593-621 (2018)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Giuseppe De Giacomo, Alfonso Gerevini, Fabio Patrizi, Alessandro Saetti, and Sebastian Sardina. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0004370215001563?via%3Dihub&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Agent planning programs&lt;/a&gt;. Artificial Intelligence, 231:64&amp;ndash;106, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sarah Hickmott and Sebastian Sardina. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://aaai.org/ocs/index.php/ICAPS/ICAPS09/paper/view/696&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Optimality properties of planning via Petri net unfolding: A formal analysis&lt;/a&gt;. In Alfonso Gerevini and Adele Howe, editors, Proceedings of the International Conference on Automated Planning and Scheduling (ICAPS), pages 170-177, Thessaloniki, Greece, September 2009. AAAI Press.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Davide Aversa, Sebastian Sardina, and Stavros Vassos. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/7860417/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Path planning with inventory-driven jump-point-search&lt;/a&gt;. In Proceedings of the AAAI-AIIDE, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agent-oriented Programming &amp; Cognitive Robotics</title>
      <link>https://ssardina.github.io/project/aoprog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ssardina.github.io/project/aoprog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am interested high-level programming languages for complex systems and intelligent agents. High-level agent-oriented programming can be seen as a middle ground between automated planning and full standard programming (e.g., Java). The idea is to write programs in a loose language so that programs will contain &amp;ldquo;gaps&amp;rdquo; that need to be filled out at execution time. These programs can typically be useful to program robotic or software agents with higher level cognitive functions that involve reasoning, for example, about goals, perception, actions, the mental states of other agents, collaborative task execution, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am interested in mainly two type of agent systems, namely, Belief-Desire-Intention (BDI) event-driven systems (like 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sarl.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SARL&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://aosgrp.com/products/jack/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;JACK&lt;/a&gt;, or 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://jason.sourceforge.net/wp/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;JASON&lt;/a&gt;) and GOLOG-type systems built on top of the famous situation calculus logical framework (like 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ssardina-agts/indigolog&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;IndiGolog&lt;/a&gt;, a high-level programming language where programs are executed incrementally to allow for interleaved action, planning, sensing, and exogenous events).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some relevant papers are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Max Waters, Lin Padgham, and Sebastian Sardina. Evaluating coverage based intention selection. In Proceedings of Autonomous Agents and Multi-Agent Systems (AAMAS), pages 957-964, Paris, France, May 2014. IFAAMAS. Nominated for Jodi Best Student Paper award.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dhirendra Singh, Sebastian Sardina, and Lin Padgham. Extending BDI plan selection to incorporate learning from experience. Journal of Robotics and Autonomous Systems, 58:1067-1075, 2010.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sebastian Sardina and Lin Padgham. A BDI agent programming language with failure recovery, declarative goals, and planning. Autonomous Agents and Multi-Agent Systems, 23(1):18-70, 2011.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Giuseppe De Giacomo, Yves Lespérance, Hector J. Levesque, and Sebastian Sardina. IndiGolog: A high-level programming language for embedded reasoning agents. In Rafael H. Bordini, Mehdi Dastani, Jürgen Dix, and Amal El Fallah-Seghrouchni, editors, Multi-Agent Programming: Languages, Platforms and Applications, chapter 2, pages 31-72. Springer, New York, USA, 2009. ISBN: 978-0-387-89298-6.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Andrea Marrella, Massimo Mecella, and Sebastian Sardina. SmartPM: An adaptive process management system through situation calculus, indigolog, and classical planning. In Chitta Baral and Giuseppe De Giacomo, editors, Proceedings of Principles of Knowledge Representation and Reasoning (KR), pages 518-527, Vienna, Austria, 2014.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI 4 Education</title>
      <link>https://ssardina.github.io/project/ai4edu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ssardina.github.io/project/ai4edu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We developed a set of 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/AI4EDUC/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;tools&lt;/a&gt; to run daily competitions in our AI courses. Students rely on an improved version of that from 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://ai.berkeley.edu/project_overview.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Berkley AI Pacman framework&lt;/a&gt;. They use search algorithms, Planning Domain Description Language (PDDL), classical replanning, minimax, reinforcement learning, and other approaches for their autonomous Pacman agents. In the course 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://ai.berkeley.edu/contest.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Capture the Flag project&lt;/a&gt;, the objective is to get home as much food as possible and prevent the other team to do so!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The code to run the competitions have been adapted over different games. This project has been developed over the years in collaboration with 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://nirlipo.github.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Dr. Nir Lipovetzky&lt;/a&gt; (Melbourne University).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every year, the top performers from both uni make it to the Hall of Fame and compete for the glory!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Behavior Composition</title>
      <link>https://ssardina.github.io/project/behcomp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ssardina.github.io/project/behcomp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With computers now present in everyday devices like mobile phones, credit cards, cars and planes or places like homes, offices and factories, the trend is to build embedded complex systems from a collection of simple components. A complex surveillance system for a smart house can be then “realised” (i.e., implemented) by suitably coordinating the behaviours (i.e., the operational logic) of hundreds (or thousands) of simple devices and artifacts (e.g., lights, blinds, a microwave, a vacuum cleaner, video cameras, a floor cleaning robot, etc.) installed in the house.  The problem then is how to automatically build an embedded controller-coordinator to bring about a desired target complex system by suitably coordinating the available components.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Behavior composition is not restricted to smart environments and can also be applied to build complex systems in advanced manufacturing systems, web-services, or even in video games, for story generation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A short (fairly easy to read) &lt;strong&gt;overview paper&lt;/strong&gt; on the topic and a more &lt;strong&gt;in-depth journal article&lt;/strong&gt; on the topic are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Giuseppe De Giacomo, Fabio Patrizi, and Sebastian Sardina. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aaai.org/ocs/index.php/ICAPS/ICAPS14/paper/view/8665&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Building virtual behaviors from partially controllable available behaviors in nondeterministic environments&lt;/a&gt;. In Proceedings of the International Conference on Automated Planning and Scheduling (ICAPS), pages 523-526, Portsmouth, NH, USA, 2014. AAAI Press.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Giuseppe De Giacomo, Fabio Patrizi, and Sebastian Sardina. 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0004370212001658?via%3Dihub&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Automatic behavior composition synthesis&lt;/a&gt;. Artificial Intelligence Journal, 196:106-142, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A tutorial on the topic delivered at IJCAI&#39;15 can be found 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sites.google.com/site/behaviorcomposition&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reasoning about action &amp; change</title>
      <link>https://ssardina.github.io/project/rac/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ssardina.github.io/project/rac/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This area is concerned with how to specify and verify dynamic systems. Different approaches to representing and reasoning about systems that change include temporal logic, model checking, dynamic logic, and modelling change in Artificial Intelligence. Some problems that I am interested include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Progression of knowledge bases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Incomplete knowledge and relation with (incomplete) databases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Knowledge precondition for plans: what knowledge is required to successfully execute a plan?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Verification of properties in dynamic systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some example of relevant papers in the area are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marcelo Arenas, Jorge A. Baier, Juan S. Navarro, Sebastian Sardiña:

&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ijcai.org/Abstract/16/133&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Incomplete Causal Laws in the Situation Calculus Using Free Fluents&lt;/a&gt;. IJCAI 2016: 907-914&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nitin Yadav and Sebastian Sardina. 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aaai.org/ocs/index.php/IJCAI/IJCAI13/paper/view/6783&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Using strategic logics to reason about agent programs&lt;/a&gt;. In Francesca Rossi, editor, Proceedings of the International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI), pages 3101-3105, Beijing, China, August 2013. AAAI Press.  In Best Papers Sister Conferences track (Best Paper Award at JELIA&#39;12).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stavros Vassos and Sebastian Sardina. [A database-type approach for progressing action theories with bounded effects](&lt;a href=&#34;https://ssardina.github.io/uploads/A_Database_type_Approach_for_Progressing.pdf&#34;&gt;). In Gerhard Lakemeyer and Sheila A. McIlraith, editors, Knowing, Reasoning, and Acting: Essays in Honour of Hector J. Levesque, chapter 29, pages 467-486. College Publications, July 2011. 

- Sebastian Sardina, Giuseppe De Giacomo, Yves Lespérance, and Hector J. Levesque. [On the limits of planning over belief states under strict uncertainty](https://www.aaai.org/Papers/KR/2006/KR06-048.pdf). In Proceedings of Principles of Knowledge Representation and Reasoning (KR), pages 463-471, Lake District, UK, June 2006.

**Obs:** picture produced by my very good friend [Diego Martinez](http://cs.uns.edu.ar/~dcm/).
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
