<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Authors | Prof. Sebastian Sardina</title>
    <link>https://ssardina.github.io/authors/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://ssardina.github.io/authors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Authors</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>2022</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://ssardina.github.io/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Authors</title>
      <link>https://ssardina.github.io/authors/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sebastian Sardina&#39;s Bio</title>
      <link>https://ssardina.github.io/author/sebastian-sardinas-bio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ssardina.github.io/author/sebastian-sardinas-bio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sebastian Sardina is a Professor in Artificial Intelligence at the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rmit.edu.au/about/schools-colleges/computing-technologies&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;School of Computing Technologies&lt;/a&gt;, RMIT University (Melbourne, AUSTRALIA). He completed his PhD at the University of Toronto (Canada) and a Bachelor in Computer Science at 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.cs.uns.edu.ar%2F&amp;amp;sa=D&amp;amp;sntz=1&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNEcIe5F9b7ZTiocf3vOSdRzwrRw-w&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;South National University&lt;/a&gt; (Bahia Blanca, Argentina).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sebastian&amp;rsquo;s research falls in the intersection between &lt;strong&gt;knowledge representation&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;AI automated planning&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;agent-oriented programming&lt;/strong&gt;, seeking better &lt;em&gt;representation&lt;/em&gt; models and &lt;em&gt;algorithms&lt;/em&gt; for &lt;strong&gt;programming intelligent controllers&lt;/strong&gt; operating in complex and dynamic environments, where the use of mainstream programming languages is difficult, cumbersome, and  error-prone. He publishes regularly in AI main scientific venues like IJCAI, AAAI, AIJ, JAIR, AAMAS, ICAPS and KR, for which he also regularly serves as Area Chair or Senior Program Committee member.  Sebastian is the Editorial Board of the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.springer.com/journal/10458&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Journal of Autonomous Agents and Multi-agent Systems (JAAMAS)&lt;/a&gt;, the premier journal in intelligent agents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At RMIT, Sebastian&amp;rsquo;s teaching focuses on the &lt;strong&gt;mathematical foundations of Computer Science&lt;/strong&gt;, in courses like Theory of Computation, Discrete Mathematics, and Artificial Intelligence. He has also delivered intense PhD/Master level courses overseas, in Italy, Spain, and Argentina. Beyond university teaching, Sebastian is also interested in bringing Computational Thinking to the community, particularly to children and youth; by delivering hands-on workshops and talks to students and educators. He has recently been part of the panel at 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vcaa.vic.edu.au/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;VCAA&lt;/a&gt; conducting the study design review for new 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/url?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.vcaa.vic.edu.au%2Fcurriculum%2Fvce%2Fvce-study-designs%2Falgorithmics%2FPages%2FIndex.aspx&amp;amp;sa=D&amp;amp;sntz=1&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNF9MxJ6dIhceC67EUfblSxoOk-tLw&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Algorithmics (HESS) VCE program&lt;/a&gt; (coming into effect in 2023).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;even-shorter&#34;&gt;Even shorter!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sebastian Sardina is a Professor in Artificial Intelligence at RMIT University within the School of Computing Technologies. He completed his PhD and M.Sc at the University of Toronto (Canada) and, before that, a BSc in Computer Science at South National University in Bahia Blanca (Argentina).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sebastian&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;research&lt;/strong&gt; falls in the intersection between knowledge representation, AI planning, and intelligent agents. In a nutshell, his research seeks better representation models and algorithms for programming intelligent controllers operating in complex and dynamic environments. His work appears regularly in the main AI scientific publication outlets, including IJCAI, AAAI, AIJ, JAIR, AAMAS, ICAPS and KR. At RMIT, Sebastian&amp;rsquo;s has been &lt;strong&gt;teaching&lt;/strong&gt; courses related to the mathematical foundations of Computer Science, such as Theory of Computation, Discrete Mathematics, and Artificial Intelligence. Beyond that, he has also been interested in &lt;strong&gt;bringing Computational Thinking to the community&lt;/strong&gt;, particularly to children and youth; by delivering hands-on workshops and talks to students and educators. He has recently been part of the panel at VCAA conducting the study design review for the new Algorithmics (HESS) VCE program.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sebastian Sardina&#39;s Bio</title>
      <link>https://ssardina.github.io/author/sebastian-sardinas-bio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ssardina.github.io/author/sebastian-sardinas-bio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am a Professor in Artificial Intelligence at the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rmit.edu.au/about/schools-colleges/computing-technologies&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;School of Computing Technologies&lt;/a&gt;, RMIT University (Melbourne, AUSTRALIA), and a member of the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.rmit.edu.au%2Failab&amp;amp;sa=D&amp;amp;sntz=1&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNFrUryBIbTz3PEERbiTB-u5IuaErw&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;RMIT AI Innovation Lab&lt;/a&gt;. I joined RMIT as a Postdoctoral Research Fellow in 2005 under a project directed by 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://goanna.cs.rmit.edu.au/linpa/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Prof. Lin Padgham&lt;/a&gt; on integrating BDI style agent-programming with AI planning approaches to sequential decision making. I completed my PhD and M.Sc in the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.cs.toronto.edu%2Fcogrobo%2Fmain%2F&amp;amp;sa=D&amp;amp;sntz=1&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNF4ymkps0mnPaTyrNmUbrh8yz4WlQ&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Cognitive Robotics Group&lt;/a&gt; at the University of Toronto (Canada) under the supervision of 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cs.toronto.edu/~hector/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Prof. Hector Levesque&lt;/a&gt;. Before that, I completed a Bachelor in Computer Science at 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.cs.uns.edu.ar%2F&amp;amp;sa=D&amp;amp;sntz=1&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNEcIe5F9b7ZTiocf3vOSdRzwrRw-w&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Universidad Nacional del Sur (South National University)&lt;/a&gt; in Bahia Blanca, Argentina, with a thesis under the advise of 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://cs.uns.edu.ar/~grs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Prof. Guillermo Simari&lt;/a&gt;. I have held Visiting Professor/Research positions at Universidad Nacional del Sur and Universidad de Buenos Aires (Argentina), Sapienza Universita’ di Roma and Free University of Bolzano-Bozen, Bolzan (Italy),  the Universidad Católica de Chile (Chile), and at Universitat Pompeu Fabra (Spain).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My &lt;strong&gt;research&lt;/strong&gt; falls in the intersection between &lt;strong&gt;knowledge representation&lt;/strong&gt; for reasoning about dynamic systems, &lt;strong&gt;AI automated planning&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;agent-oriented programming&lt;/strong&gt;. In a nutshell, my research seeks better &lt;em&gt;representation&lt;/em&gt; models and &lt;em&gt;algorithms&lt;/em&gt; for &lt;strong&gt;programming intelligent controllers&lt;/strong&gt; operating in complex and dynamic environments, in which an agent must plan, verify, execute, monitor, and reconsider its actions so as to achieve its goals. Developing such controllers in standard programming languages (like C++, Python, or JAVA) becomes a difficult, cumbersome, and an error-prone task, so we look for better ways to do that! My work is regularly published at AI scientific venues like IJCAI, AAAI, AIJ, JAIR, AAMAS, ICAPS and KR, but I have also published in non-AI outlets like IEEE SOCA, BPM, CIG, IEEE Transactions on Automatic Control, and Journal of Robotics and Autonomous Systems. In my research, I have extensively collaborated with many academics in research, most notably with 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.diag.uniroma1.it/degiacom/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Prof. Giuseppe De Giacomo&lt;/a&gt; and his group at Sapienza Universita&#39; di Roma, Italy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of &lt;strong&gt;teaching&lt;/strong&gt;, I have taught at RMIT courses that are mostly related to the &lt;strong&gt;mathematical foundations of Computer Science&lt;/strong&gt;, such as Theory of Computation, Discrete Mathematics, and Artificial Intelligence. I have also taught two seminar research style courses, namely, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://bit.ly/3qvGmj6&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;COSC1204/2048 Agent-oriented Programming &amp;amp; Design&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://bit.ly/2WI3XjR&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;COSC2780 Intelligent Decision Making&lt;/a&gt;. In the past I have been the Program Manager for the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rmit.edu.au/study-with-us/levels-of-study/undergraduate-study/honours-degrees/bachelor-of-science-honours-bh012&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;BH013 Honours in Computer Science&lt;/a&gt; and BP232 Computing Studies (currently discontinued). Besides RMIT, I have delivered intense advanced courses overseas at Sapienza Universita&#39; di Roma (Italy), Universidad de Buenos Aires (Argentina), as part of their long-standing 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://eci.dc.uba.ar/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ECI serie&lt;/a&gt;, and Universidad Autónoma de Barcelona (Spain), under the ERASMUS+ scheme. I have also run staff training workshops at 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://aosgrp.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Agent-oriented Software&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a Computer Scientist, I am also very interested in &lt;strong&gt;bringing Computational Thinking and programming to the community&lt;/strong&gt;, particularly to children and youth. I have delivered or supported courses and workshops on algorithmic thinking and coding in Melbourne (in primary and secondary schools as well as in community centres) and provided outreach activities from RMIT to the community.  I have helped promote (or tried to!) the integration of Computational Thinking with the Math teaching at the Mathematical Association of Victoria 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mav.vic.edu.au/Conference/Previous-Annual-Conferences&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;annual conferences&lt;/a&gt; (the premier forum for math educators in Victoria), running workshops, presentations, and participating in panel of experts discussions. During 2020-201, I have been a member of the panel at 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vcaa.vic.edu.au/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;VCAA&lt;/a&gt; conducting the study design review for the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/url?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.vcaa.vic.edu.au%2Fcurriculum%2Fvce%2Fvce-study-designs%2Falgorithmics%2FPages%2FIndex.aspx&amp;amp;sa=D&amp;amp;sntz=1&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNF9MxJ6dIhceC67EUfblSxoOk-tLw&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Algorithmics (HESS) VCE program&lt;/a&gt; which would come into effect in 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of &lt;strong&gt;processional service&lt;/strong&gt;, I have been in the organization committee of various events, including IJCAI’17 (Exhibition Chair), AAMAS&#39;16 (Tutorial Chair), AAAI&#39;15 (Student Abstract and Poster Track Chair), and AAMAS&#39;15 (Student Travel Support). I have organised several international workshops and I am a regular Area Chair/Senior Program Committee/Program Committee for top-rated conferneces like IJCAI, AAAI, AAMAS, KR, and ICAPS, among others. I am currently in the Editorial Board of the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.springer.com/journal/10458&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Journal of Autonomous Agents and Multi-agent Systems (JAAMAS)&lt;/a&gt;, and often review for major journals such as AJ and JAIR.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
