<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Authors | Prof. Sebastian Sardina</title>
    <link>https://ssardina.github.io/authors/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://ssardina.github.io/authors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Authors</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>2022</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://ssardina.github.io/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Authors</title>
      <link>https://ssardina.github.io/authors/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sebastian Sardina&#39;s Bio</title>
      <link>https://ssardina.github.io/author/sebastian-sardinas-bio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ssardina.github.io/author/sebastian-sardinas-bio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am a Professor in Artificial Intelligence at the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rmit.edu.au/about/schools-colleges/computing-technologies&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;School of Computing Technologies&lt;/a&gt;, RMIT Unviersity (Melbourne, AUSTRALIA), and a member of the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.rmit.edu.au%2Failab&amp;amp;sa=D&amp;amp;sntz=1&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNFrUryBIbTz3PEERbiTB-u5IuaErw&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;RMIT AI Innovation Lab&lt;/a&gt;. I joined RMIT as a Postdoctoral Research Fellow in 2005 under a project directed by 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://goanna.cs.rmit.edu.au/linpa/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Prof. Lin Padgham&lt;/a&gt; on integrating BDI style agent-programming with AI planning approaches to sequential decision making. I completed my PhD and M.Sc in the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.cs.toronto.edu%2Fcogrobo%2Fmain%2F&amp;amp;sa=D&amp;amp;sntz=1&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNF4ymkps0mnPaTyrNmUbrh8yz4WlQ&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Cognitive Robotics Group&lt;/a&gt; at the University of Toronto (Canada) under the supervision of 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cs.toronto.edu/~hector/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Prof. Hector Levesque&lt;/a&gt;. Before that, I completed a Bachelor in Computer Science at 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.cs.uns.edu.ar%2F&amp;amp;sa=D&amp;amp;sntz=1&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNEcIe5F9b7ZTiocf3vOSdRzwrRw-w&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Universidad Nacional del Sur&lt;/a&gt; in Bahia Blanca, Argentina, with a thesis under the advise of 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://cs.uns.edu.ar/~grs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Prof. Guillermo Simari&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My research falls in the intersection between &lt;strong&gt;knowledge representation&lt;/strong&gt; for reasoning about dynamic systems, &lt;strong&gt;AI automated planning&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;agent-oriented programming&lt;/strong&gt;. In a nutshell, my research seeks better &lt;em&gt;representation&lt;/em&gt; models and &lt;em&gt;algorithms&lt;/em&gt; for &lt;strong&gt;programming intelligent controllers&lt;/strong&gt; operating in complex and dynamic environments, in which an agent must plan, verify, execute, monitor, and reconsider its actions so as to achieve its goals. Developing such controllers in standard programming languages (like C++, Python, or JAVA) becomes a difficult, cumbersome, and an error-prone task, so we look for better ways to do that! I have extensively collaborated with many academics in research, most notably with 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.diag.uniroma1.it/degiacom/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Prof. Giuseppe De Giacomo&lt;/a&gt; at Sapienza Universita&#39; di Roma, Italy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At RMIT I have taught several courses, mostly related to the &lt;strong&gt;mathematical foundations of Computer Science&lt;/strong&gt; (Theory of Computation, Discrete Mathematics, and Artificial Intelligence). I have also taught two seminar research style courses, namely, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://bit.ly/3qvGmj6&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;COSC1204/2048 Agent-oriented Programming &amp;amp; Design&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://bit.ly/2WI3XjR&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;COSC2780 Intelligent Decision Making&lt;/a&gt;. In the past I have been the Program Manager for the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rmit.edu.au/study-with-us/levels-of-study/undergraduate-study/honours-degrees/bachelor-of-science-honours-bh012&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;BH013 Honours in Computer Science&lt;/a&gt; and BP232 Computing Studies (currently discontinued).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a Computer Scientist, I am also very interested in &lt;strong&gt;bringing Computational Thinking and programming to the community&lt;/strong&gt;, particularly to children and youth. I have delivered or supported courses and workshops on algorithmic thinking and coding in Melbourne (in primary and secondary schools as well as in community centres) and provided outreach activities from RMIT to the community.  I have helped promote (or tried to!) the integration of Computational Thinking with the Math teaching at the Mathematical Association of Victoria 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mav.vic.edu.au/Conference/Previous-Annual-Conferences&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;annual conferences&lt;/a&gt; (the premier forum for math educators in Victoria), running workshops, presentations, and participating in panel of experts discussions. During 2020-201, I have been a member of the panel at 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vcaa.vic.edu.au/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;VCAA&lt;/a&gt; conducting the study design review for the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/url?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.vcaa.vic.edu.au%2Fcurriculum%2Fvce%2Fvce-study-designs%2Falgorithmics%2FPages%2FIndex.aspx&amp;amp;sa=D&amp;amp;sntz=1&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNF9MxJ6dIhceC67EUfblSxoOk-tLw&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Algorithmics (HESS) VCE program&lt;/a&gt; which would come into effect in 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
