<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages | Prof. Sebastian Sardina</title>
    <link>https://ssardina.github.io/pages/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://ssardina.github.io/pages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Pages</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>2022</copyright>
    <image>
      <url>https://ssardina.github.io/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Pages</title>
      <link>https://ssardina.github.io/pages/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sebastian Sardina&#39;s Extended Bio</title>
      <link>https://ssardina.github.io/pages/ssardina_bio_long/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ssardina.github.io/pages/ssardina_bio_long/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sebastian Sardina is a Professor in Artificial Intelligence at the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rmit.edu.au/about/schools-colleges/computing-technologies&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;School of Computing Technologies&lt;/a&gt;, RMIT University (Melbourne, AUSTRALIA), and a member of the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.rmit.edu.au%2Failab&amp;amp;sa=D&amp;amp;sntz=1&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNFrUryBIbTz3PEERbiTB-u5IuaErw&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;RMIT AI Innovation Lab&lt;/a&gt;. He joined RMIT as a Postdoctoral Research Fellow in 2005 under a project directed by 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://goanna.cs.rmit.edu.au/linpa/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Prof. Lin Padgham&lt;/a&gt; on integrating BDI style agent-programming with AI planning approaches to sequential decision making. He completed his PhD and M.Sc in the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.cs.toronto.edu%2Fcogrobo%2Fmain%2F&amp;amp;sa=D&amp;amp;sntz=1&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNF4ymkps0mnPaTyrNmUbrh8yz4WlQ&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Cognitive Robotics Group&lt;/a&gt; at the University of Toronto (Canada) under the supervision of 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cs.toronto.edu/~hector/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Prof. Hector Levesque&lt;/a&gt;. Before that, he obtained a Bachelor in Computer Science from the 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/url?q=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.cs.uns.edu.ar%2F&amp;amp;sa=D&amp;amp;sntz=1&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNEcIe5F9b7ZTiocf3vOSdRzwrRw-w&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;South National University (Universidad Nacional del Sur)&lt;/a&gt; in Bahia Blanca, Argentina, with a thesis under the advise of 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://cs.uns.edu.ar/~grs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Prof. Guillermo Simari&lt;/a&gt;. Sebastian has held Visiting Professor/Research positions at Universidad Nacional del Sur and Universidad de Buenos Aires (Argentina), Sapienza Universita’ di Roma and Free University of Bolzano-Bozen, Bolzan (Italy),  the Universidad Católica de Chile (Chile), and at Universitat Pompeu Fabra (Spain).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sebastian&amp;rsquo;s research&lt;/strong&gt; falls in the intersection between &lt;strong&gt;knowledge representation&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;AI automated planning&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;agent-oriented programming&lt;/strong&gt;, seeking better &lt;em&gt;representation&lt;/em&gt; models and &lt;em&gt;algorithms&lt;/em&gt; for &lt;strong&gt;programming goal-oriented controllers&lt;/strong&gt; operating in dynamic environments, where the use of mainstream programming languages (like C++, Python, or JAVA) is difficult, cumbersome, and  error-prone. Sebastian has contributed to the enhancement of agent programming languages with learning and planning capabilities, and to the study and development of advanced forms of AI planning, including non-deterministic planning and automatic behaviour composition of devices and agents. In recent years, he has significantly contributed to the the goal/intention recognition problem. Sebastian&amp;rsquo;s research has been carried out with a many collaborators and students around the world, for which he feels extremely &lt;em&gt;lucky&lt;/em&gt; and grateful!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sebastian scientific contributions regularly appear in premier AI scientific publication outlets, including IJCAI, AAMAS, ICAPS, KR, AIJ, JAIR, JAAMAS, and AAAI, for which he also regularly serves as Area Chair or Senior Program Committee member. He has also published in non-AI venues like IEEE SOCA, BPM, CIG, IEEE Transactions on Automatic Control, and Journal of Robotics and Autonomous Systems. His work has received paper awards/recognition (or nominations for) at ICAPS&#39;21, AAMAS&#39;19, AAMAS&#39;17, IJCNN&#39;17, AAMAS&#39;14, and JELIA&#39;12, and has been invited for presentation nationally and internationally at various forums and institutions.  Sebastian is in the Editorial Board of the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.springer.com/journal/10458&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Journal of Autonomous Agents and Multi-agent Systems (JAAMAS)&lt;/a&gt;, the premier journal in intelligent agents, and has been in the organization committee of various top-rated AI conferences (e.g., KR&#39;18 Tutorial &amp;amp; Workshop Chair, IJCAI’17 as Exhibition Chair, AAMAS&#39;16 as Tutorial Chair, AAAI&#39;15 as Student Abstract and Poster Track Chair, and AAMAS&#39;15 as Student Travel Support Coordinator), for which he also regularly serves as Area Chair or Senior Program Committee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sebastian Sardina&amp;rsquo;s teaching&lt;/strong&gt; at RMIT has focused on courses related to the &lt;strong&gt;mathematical foundations of Computer Science&lt;/strong&gt;, such as Theory of Computation, Discrete Mathematics, and Artificial Intelligence. He have also taught two seminar research-style courses, namely, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://bit.ly/3qvGmj6&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;COSC1204/2048 Agent-oriented Programming &amp;amp; Design&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://bit.ly/2WI3XjR&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;COSC2780 Intelligent Decision Making&lt;/a&gt;. In the past, he has have been the Program Manager for the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rmit.edu.au/study-with-us/levels-of-study/undergraduate-study/honours-degrees/bachelor-of-science-honours-bh012&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;BH013 Honours in Computer Science&lt;/a&gt; and BP232 Computing Studies (currently discontinued). Besides RMIT, he has delivered intense advanced courses overseas at Sapienza Universita&#39; di Roma (Italy), Universidad de Buenos Aires (Argentina), as part of their long-standing 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://eci.dc.uba.ar/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ECI serie&lt;/a&gt;, and Universidad Autónoma de Barcelona (Spain), under the ERASMUS+ scheme, as well as staff training workshops at 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://aosgrp.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Agent-oriented Software&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More generally, as a Computer Scientist, Sebastian Sardina has also been interested in &lt;strong&gt;bringing Computational Thinking and programming to the community&lt;/strong&gt;, particularly to children and youth. He has delivered or supported courses and workshops on algorithmic thinking and coding in Melbourne (in primary and secondary schools as well as in community centres) and provided outreach activities from RMIT to the community.  He has helped (or tried to!) promote the integration of Computational Thinking with the Math teaching at the Mathematical Association of Victoria 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mav.vic.edu.au/Conference/Previous-Annual-Conferences&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;annual conferences&lt;/a&gt; (the premier forum for math educators in Victoria), running workshops, presentations, and participating in panel of experts discussions. During 2020-2021, I have been a member of the panel at 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vcaa.vic.edu.au/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;VCAA&lt;/a&gt; conducting the study design review for the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/url?q=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.vcaa.vic.edu.au%2Fcurriculum%2Fvce%2Fvce-study-designs%2Falgorithmics%2FPages%2FIndex.aspx&amp;amp;sa=D&amp;amp;sntz=1&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNF9MxJ6dIhceC67EUfblSxoOk-tLw&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Algorithmics (HESS) VCE program&lt;/a&gt; which would come into effect in 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Too long? Check 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ssardina.github.io/pages/ssardina_bio_short/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sebastian Sardina&#39;s Short Bio</title>
      <link>https://ssardina.github.io/pages/ssardina_bio_short/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ssardina.github.io/pages/ssardina_bio_short/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sebastian Sardina is a Professor in Artificial Intelligence at RMIT University within the School of Computing Technologies. He completed his PhD and M.Sc at the University of Toronto (Canada) and, before that, a BSc in Computer Science at South National University in Bahia Blanca (Argentina).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sebastian&amp;rsquo;s research falls in the intersection between &lt;em&gt;knowledge representation&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;AI planning&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;intelligent agents&lt;/em&gt;. His research seeks better &lt;em&gt;representation models&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;algorithms&lt;/em&gt; for programming goal-oriented controllers operating in dynamic environments. Together with his many collaborators and students (for which he feels extremely &lt;em&gt;lucky&lt;/em&gt; and grateful!), he has contributed significantly to the integration of agent programming languages with planning and learning capabilities, the study and development of advanced forms of planning, and the development of goal/intention recognition techniques for intelligent agents. His work appears regularly in the main AI scientific publication outlets, such as IJCAI, AAAI, AIJ, JAIR, AAMAS, ICAPS and KR, and many of his papers have received paper awards or nominations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sebastian&amp;rsquo;s teaching has focused on course related to the &lt;em&gt;mathematical foundations of Computer Science&lt;/em&gt;. He has also been involved in &lt;em&gt;bringing Computational Thinking to the community&lt;/em&gt;, particularly to children and youth, by delivering hands-on workshops and talks to students and educators. He has recently been part of the panel at VCAA conducting the study design review for the new Algorithmics (HESS) VCE program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;an-an-even-shorter-one&#34;&gt;An an even shorter one!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sebastian Sardina is a Professor in Artificial Intelligence at RMIT University, with a PhD from the University of Toronto (Canada) and a Bachelor from the South National University (Argentina). Sebastian&amp;rsquo;s research falls in the intersection between knowledge representation, AI planning, and intelligent agents, seeking representation models and algorithms for programming complex controllers in dynamic systems. At uni, he teaches courses related to the mathematical foundations of Computer Science; outside uni he tries to bring Computational Thinking closer to children and youth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;too-boring&#34;&gt;Too &amp;ldquo;boring&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sebastian Sardina has unintentionally &amp;ldquo;grew&amp;rdquo; from a child liking Computers and Coding to a Professor in AI at RMIT University in Melbourne, Australia. He is extremely grateful to many (and a LOT to some who need not to be mentioned) who inspired, helped, and supported him all the way, from his Bachelor in CS in Argentina to his Master and PhD in Canada to his postdoc and more in Australia. He is somehow known for his work in AI knowledge representation, planning, and agent programming on models and algorithms for reasoning about dynamic systems. He is also known (by many students) for his math-oriented courses and recently for his efforts to bring Computational Thinking to younger people in the community.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
